♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 7]
I drew these for fun
when I had free time.
Then why didn't you draw the face?
Do you want me to ask further
whose face these are supposed to be?
You are the Crown Prince!
I'm sorry.
I will obey what you say, Mother.
I won't draw again.
What about the Shijia Town?
Chengze was alerted.
By the time my men arrived,
his men had already retreated.
They didn't leave any evidence
in the town.
If so, why did you burn down the town?
Because Fan Xian is a good man.
Only if I burned the town to the ground
would he be driven apart from Chengze
and firmly take my side.
All the more reason
he can't find out the truth.
Don't worry, Mother.
Except for a lunatic,
no one would do such an atrocious
and vile deed
for no reason.
There is only one truth.
Chengze wiped out the town.
Why do you value Fan Xian so much?
No one would turn down a good man.
Mr. Fan.
I have been waiting for you.
Didn't I ask you to go home
and consider it?
There would only be dangers
if you follow me.
I have thought it through.
That's quick.
There is not much to consider.
My wife said
I could make this much money
in a month,
which no other place could offer.
One more thing.
You are
a good man.
What's the point of being a good man
when dangers surround me?
Mr. Fan,
dangers lurk everywhere,
but good men are few and far between.
Speaking of which,
what kind of good man am I?
There are enough things wrong with me.
I'm cowardly,
selfish,
greedy, and vain.
I'm at times resistant to change
and indecisive.
In all honesty,
I'm just an ordinary man.
What will an ordinary man do
in this situation?
What will they do?
They quit!
I'm no longer the inspector,
and the trail has gone cold.
I can't continue the investigation.
Why should I continue?
How is that my concern?
People should learn
how to keep their hands clean.
Mr. Fan,
please don't be discouraged.
Your dispositions and stances
have already changed many people.
Who?
At least, there is me,
Wang Qinian.
It seems that you haven't figured out
His Majesty's intention.
I did.
He took my official token away
[Imperial Inspectorate]
and appointed a marriage
between Li Chengze and the Ye family.
Everyone knows that the Ye family
is protected by a Grandmaster.
Once they get married,
Li Chengze will have a promising future.
His Majesty
is protecting him.
He thinks it's unfair.
I can't afford that thought.
What's his identity?
And what is mine?
It's a given
that His Majesty protects his own son.
So you are not going to continue
the investigation?
Mr. Chen, how am I going to continue?
The prince broke the law.
I risked my life to advise the emperor.
He refused to listen.
Fine, I obeyed him.
Now, I came back here alive
to tell him the hard truth again,
but he still deflected the topic.
Is anything I say useful?
Who can I trust in this world?
Can I trust him?
Can I trust you?
It doesn't matter
whether you trust me or not.
[Inspector]
I brought this back for you.
His Majesty threw it into the water.
But did he ever mention dismissing you?
Everyone can see that what His Majesty
had said earlier today
was to protect Li Chengze.
So, from now on,
this matter is considered over.
That's a subtle hint.
His Majesty wants me to lie low
and find something in the undercurrent.
No wonder he threw it into the water.
Don't read too much into it.
You are going too far.
Anyway, you got the right message.
But the Shijia Town is gone.
If you don't calm yourself down,
more towns will end up like Shijia Town.
The priority now is,
do you really know
who you are up against?
Have you ever considered
your future actions?
Who I'm against
is Li Chengze
and people of his kind.
I'm not my mother.
I can't live by the goal
of changing this world.
But at least
in this life,
I want to be a good man
I identify myself to be
and live with a conscience
I'm comfortable with.
I hate to see
unjust deaths like Teng Zijing's,
nor do I want to witness
defenseless people like Jin.
I want to speak up for them.
I want to seek justice
for those who die aggrieved.
That's why you must calm down,
lie low,
and start over.
Although the inspector
of the Imperial Inspectorate is powerful,
you are on your own.
You have been in the Capital
for some time.
You should have your own team.
I have Wang Qinian.
Not enough.
Do you remember Zhu Ge?
I won't forget him.
After Zhu Ge's passing,
the First Division
has been without a leader.
I suggest you
take up his position.
The First Division monitors
the officials in the Capital,
which involves complicated parties.
This is a place of trouble
and fierce battles.
Just now, you said
you wanted to speak up for the people
and bring Li Chengze down.
This position
is the best choice.
Mr. Chen,
I heard something
during the trip to Northern Qi.
It's good.
You got to see the real world.
Is my life
controlled by you all?
If I say I'm helping you,
would you believe me?
Do I have the guts to believe you?
After all, you are her son.
There is something
I have been meaning to ask.
Go on.
If one day
I pick a different path
from my mother's,
who would you choose?
Impossible.
What if it were true?
I would definitely choose your mother.
In the end, you all help me
because I'm her son.
Exactly.
Then you will be disappointed.
I'm not the same as my mother.
You should know
there is no one alike in this world.
But you and your mother
are the same in nature.
I wouldn't dare to erupt this monument.
It doesn't matter
whether you erupt a monument or not.
Listen, you will surely walk the same path
as your mother in the future.
Besides, I'm now trying
to make sure
you will walk the path you choose.
I have been manipulated all my life,
yet I have to make sure
I walk the path I choose,
isn't that absurd?
To gain, you must first give.
This isn't absurd.
Have you thought this through
long ago?
I have told you.
Whatever you want to do,
I will always be there for you.
I may have deceived you before,
but I mean what I'm saying now.
Is there anything else
you are keeping from me?
Of course, there is.
But I can't tell you.
Can I still trust you?
Yes,
but not completely.
You can never tell with people,
after all.
[Inspector]
If so,
I will trust you halfway.
That's too much.
Is this the old one?
The person eager to see you more
than I am has come.
Leave no loose ends
on the Baoyue Pleasure House.
I know.
What brings you here?
This is Fan Xian.
His surname is Fan. He is my son.
I know.
No one wants to take him away from you.
What is the highest virtue
in the Qing State's culture?
Is it filial piety?
Have you heard of familial love?
I did.
The first people he met after traveling
all the way back to the Capital
were His Majesty and you.
This is ridiculous.
Why is he so angry?
I'm not angry.
Why would I be?
I'm reasoning with you.
Let me ask you this.
After returning from a long journey,
Fan Xian didn't first return home
to pay respects to the family.
Isn't this against
the teaching of filial piety?
If this gets out,
will the Ministry of Rites
criticize him?
You are right. They will.
Finally, you admit you are wrong.
But I didn't summon him here.
Not you?
Actually, I came here myself.
I wanted to wipe this monument.
Let's go home.
You are riding with me.
Please have some tea.
Don't fuss over
what happened in the palace.
Even though His Majesty
got rid of your token,
he didn't issue an order.
To remove me
from the position of inspector.
Mr. Chen told me about that.
This is the Capital.
It's not a battle between two fighters.
If you want to compete
with the Second Prince,
don't do it yourself.
I need to cultivate my own team.
Mr. Chen told me about that too.
Afterward, I will take up the position
in the First Division.
I know Mr. Chen is helping you.
But this is the Capital.
You ought to be careful.
I can trust Mr. Chen,
but not completely.
You can never tell with people.
He mentioned this as well.
How generous of him.
But there is one thing
I don't hold with.
Which one?
You can never tell with people.
For others,
I can't trust them completely.
But not my family.
Those fellows in the Ministry of Rites
always make a fuss about filial piety.
I hurried here
not because you didn't pay me respect.
I'm afraid you might mistrust people
in the court.
Father, thank you for your wise advice.
I'm so enlightened
upon hearing it.
As long as you understand.
I haven't visited Wan'er
since I returned here.
Maybe...
Maybe I should stay at home
for a few days first
before I visit her.
You should go back and visit Ruoruo.
Your little sister has
missed you terribly.
[Fan's Residence]
Ruoruo.
Xian, you are finally back.
Where have you been?
I...
I was wandering the world.
Wander the world?
For how long?
Around
fifteen minutes.
That's quite a short journey.
In fact,
I wasn't just wandering the world.
I was trying to avoid the marriage.
I heard that His Majesty appointed
a marriage for me.
But I don't want it,
so I packed my things and ran away.
Then, why did you come back?
I left in haste,
and when I calmed down halfway,
I came to a realization.
Xian,
do you know who I trust the most
in this world?
Who?
You, of course.
So I was thinking of asking
for your opinion
whether I should leave or not.
What if I ask you to stay?
What are you doing?
Since I'm not leaving,
I will put the clothes back
in the chest.
Aren't you worried that I make you
follow the decree to get married?
Not at all, Xian.
Like I said,
you are the one
I trust the most in this world.
Ruoruo, you don't want to get married?
No.
Got it.
Don't worry. I will find a way.
You won't get married
if you don't want to.
Sure.
If things can't work out,
I will take you and run.
All right.
Stop. You will mess up my hair.
Well, continue with the unpacking.
I'm off to handle Fan Sizhe's matter.
Xian,
you just got back.
What's wrong with Fan Sizhe?
Is it a serious matter?
Let me put it this way.
I almost beat him to death.
I have often thought that.
I can help you with that.
It's a misunderstanding.
Well, let's do it another time, then.
Don't forget to call me next time.
But he is your little brother.
You are my elder brother.
Can't you be more fair?
I can't.
I may have many younger brothers
in days to come,
but you are my only elder brother.
That does make some sense.
Ruoruo,
don't worry. I won't let you down.
Of course you won't.
You say Fan Xian is back?
Yes, Young Master.
My father must be elated, right?
Father, did you ask for me?
Mother, you are here too.
Xian, you are finally back.
Why are you kneeling
before he asks anything?
I sense this familiar tension.
Do you know
about the Baoyue Pleasure House?
I do.
Who is the owner?
It's me.
This is simply ludicrous!
How could you do that?
Mother,
I just wanted to make some money.
You lost your character for mere money.
Master, please spare him.
Run.
Bring torture.
No need.
Actually, he is also the victim.
That's right.
Sizhe is never smart.
Surely, he was deceived.
Mother, you always call me smart.
Just shut up already.
Whether or not he was deceived,
he must accept the punishment
for his mistake.
He will be beaten
no matter what.
To be honest, I have already beaten him.
Yes, Fan Xian already...
You beat him?
Did you both meet before?
Yes.
He almost beat me to death.
Why didn't you tell me?
Xian said not to tell anyone
and wanted me to stay in my room.
So you didn't go out these days
because of Fan Xian?
You have already returned
to the Capital earlier?
I did come back before.
What is going on?
Father, it is a long story.
Don't let him keep kneeling.
Stand over there.
Well,
it's all because
the Second Prince set me up.
[Fan's Residence]
Anyway, this is what happened.
He didn't know about the prostitution
in the Baoyue Pleasure House.
Father, you heard him.
I truly had no idea about that.
If the Baoyue Pleasure House
were to be exposed,
you would be the first one under arrest.
Please, Father.
They didn't tell me it was a brothel.
They said it was just a place
for listening to songs and chatting.
I...
What should we do, then?
Actually,
this can be over
if I compromise or yield.
That's impossible.
Aunt, do you trust me so much?
You have never compromised or yielded.
Have you come up
with a solution for Sizhe?
Making a clear break
with the Baoyue Pleasure House
within a short time
isn't realistic.
To keep him safe,
he has to leave the Capital.
You are right.
I will accompany Sizhe
and hide in Danzhou for a while.
He can't stay in the Qing State.
Where else could he go, then?
Head northward.
Go to Northern Qi.
That's too far away.
That's good.
I will accompany Sizhe
to go to the north.
Aunt, you can't go with him.
He has to go there alone.
Why not?
Why?
This is a secret move,
not a vacation.
You are the daughter
of the duke after all.
Everyone knows your face.
Still, Sizhe can't go
to Northern Qi alone.
He has never left the Capital before.
Fan Sizhe.
Are you afraid?
A bit.
I know
it's very difficult for you
to suddenly leave a comfortable home
and go on a long
and unknown journey alone
without help.
Stop... Stop saying.
You are making me more scared.
But this is also an opportunity for you.
How is this an opportunity?
One will never grow up
if they don't leave home.
Have you ever thought
of proving yourself to someone?
To prove that you are not a kid anymore.
To prove
that not everything you do is wrong.
And to prove
that you deserve expectations.
I want to prove myself.
Go to the north, then.
Find your own path.
He can't do this.
All right.
Louder.
I can't hear you.
I can do this!
I made a mistake,
so I must bear the consequences.
Father,
I will go to Northern Qi.
But you have fear.
Mother,
I do have fear.
But I can't always stand behind you.
I have already grown all up.
When should he depart?
Tonight.
So soon?
The sooner, the better, Mother.
I'm afraid I might change my mind
a few days later.
Xian, is the weather in Northern Qi
very cold?
It's quite cold.
All right. I will go get
some more thick clothes.
I'm running out of time.
How come he just changed
all of a sudden?
Aunt,
sometimes, it only takes a moment
for a man to grow up.
No, I must remind him something.
This is sudden.
In the end,
I got him involved in this.
You were right.
What?
It takes only a moment for a man
to grow up.
Destiny always strikes us unprepared.
This brat doesn't disappoint me.
That's my son.
You should say this
to him in person.
Remember to dress warmly
when the weather is cold.
Don't skip meals.
All right, Mother.
Don't see me off.
I would change my mind and stay.
Well, then.
All right, stop crying.
You will get wrinkles.
Bite your tongue.
I'm leaving, Mother.
Father.
Fan Xian said
I should tell you this in person.
The carriage is ready.
Thank you, Father.
One more thing.
You didn't let me down.
Fan Sizhe,
you are my son.
Safe journey.
Your mother and I
will wait for you to come home.
What are you looking at?
I'm looking at the rain.
I grew up in the Capital.
I have seen all kinds of rain,
and I'm fed up of them.
Somehow, I couldn't stop looking
at the rain today.
Just consider that the Capital is crying
to send you off.
Why don't you cry it out?
I don't want to.
I'm a grown-up now.
Grown-ups don't cry.
They do cry.
Sometimes, grown-ups
can be a crier.
Xian, let's cry together.
I'm not going northward.
Why should I cry?
Can't you speak anything nicer?
What is this?
Bank notes?
Well... Are these all mine?
This is the capital.
Once you arrive in Northern Qi,
your first mission is to make money.
You decide what business you want.
If anything happens,
you take care of it.
Don't forget you want to prove to Father
and yourself.
I know. Don't worry about me.
Don't forget to return the money to me.
This is an investment.
If you make profits,
I will take dividends.
We are brothers.
Do we have to keep it strictly business?
If you say so, give me back the money.
No...
Don't worry.
I will make sure you get dividends.
You say this is my first mission.
What about the second mission?
Do you still remember Guo Baokun?
He's also in Northern Qi.
No way.
What do you mean?
You beat him up to a pulp.
Do you still have to go hard on him?
He is working for me now.
Seriously?
Once you arrive in Northern Qi,
look for Guo Baokun immediately.
And then?
Remember what I'm going to tell you.
Keep it between us.
Can I tell Guo Baokun about it?
Keep it between you and I.
You need to be precise.
Pipe down.
I'm counting on you, guys.
Please don't say that, Inspector.
They will be escorting you to the north.
They will look after you on the way.
Who are they?
Don't forget what I told you.
Safe journey. Go ahead.
Please take care of my mother.
Don't worry. I have got it.
Thank you, Xian.
I will remember the money you gave me.
Rest assured.
I will make profits.
Don't worry.
Those are the skilled fighters
from the Fourth Division.
Your brother will be fine.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
If it weren't
for Mr. Chen's instruction,
I couldn't care less about you.
I will start my new post
in the First Division tomorrow.
Do you want to come and take a look?
[Imperial courtyard,
Lin Wan'er's residence]
Fan Xian, right?
Ye Ling'er.
Looks like I have to refine
my light body skills.
- Hurry over.
- Where is Wan'er?
I have something to tell you.
What is it about? Where is Wan'er?
Don't deflect. I'm forgetful.
[Ye Ling'er, daughter of Ye Zhong]
Wan'er knew you would come,
[the Grand Commandant of the Capital]
so she hid away.
Why is Wan'er avoiding me?
She wants me to tell you this.
First, Wan'er knows you love her
very much.
So does she.
Second, because of the first point,
she's worried about you
as you might face dangers
after you just got back here.
She hopes you can focus
on dealing with them.
Third, because of the first two points,
you shouldn't come here.
She won't meet you for now.
Did Wan'er say all this?
This is my interpretation
of what she said.
She said
you would understand her.
There is one more thing.
What is that again?
She said
she would always be with you.
I know.
Could you please
relay a message to her?
Sure, go on.
First,
I miss you.
Second,
don't worry.
Why aren't you making notes?
It's short. I can remember.
Right.
You may leave.
I really don't get you.
Just meet with him if you want to.
Why are you standing here
with those dewy eyes of yours?
Given the current situation,
he should focus on his problem.
I fear I would keep him
after meeting him.
[Lin Wan'er, daughter
of Prime Minster Lin Ruofu]
I envy you two so much.
I won't have such luck
in my life.
Ling'er,
if you can't accept the marriage
appointed by His Majesty,
let's go to the palace tomorrow
and implore His Majesty
to annul it.
My father won't agree with that.
I have made up my mind.
I would rather just take my life.
Please don't.
My family is already preparing
for the engagement.
I'm really upset seeing that.
Can I stay at your place
for a few days?
You can stay here as long as you want.
Father.
I'm back.
Which cell are you in?
I'm all right now.
I came to fetch you home.
Good to know that.
You may go.
I'm doing pretty well here.
I'm not going back.
Have you ever considered
the consequence of helping Fan Xian
fake his death?
Fan Xian went to the palace
and confessed to his crime
of deceiving the emperor.
You do know that, huh?
This crime
often brings destruction
to the whole clan.
Why am I here?
Do you think I'm putting on a show?
I'm preparing to pay myself
for you what did.
I sorted it out.
At worst, I would take my life
to spare the family.
You sorted it out, you say?
Can you sort out
the laws of the Qing State
and His Majesty's mind?
If anything were to go wrong,
I would take the blame all by myself.
Do you think so highly of yourself
that you would sacrifice your own life
and end everything?
That was a desperate choice.
Just how desperate were you
that you wouldn't consider
the consequences?
It concerns a prince's treason.
You could've returned
to the Capital first.
It was related to the Qing State,
and I couldn't just sit tight.
In that case,
did you do that for the Qing State?
This is the very reason
for what I have done so far.
You would rather deceive the emperor
for the sake of the Qing State?
The state is beyond everything.
What about His Majesty?
His Majesty would certainly care
about the state, but...
But he can't be more important
than the state itself.
How dare you, Yan Bingyun!
You taught me this.
The state is above all else.
At least you are cautious
when you say things
like that.
I'm not that dull.
Come.
I doubt it.
Why did you help him?
I didn't help him.
I did it for the Qing State.
But you were assisting him.
Yes.
He may be
ridiculous,
but
he is bold.
So
you are willing to advise him?
Why would I advise him?
He probably will
take over the Imperial Inspectorate
in the future.
Mr. Chen is irreplaceable.
We are getting old.
Does Mr. Chen intend to retire?
It's not just Chen Pingping.
I wish to retire too.
It's time to hand
the Imperial Inspectorate
to youngsters like you all.
Your retirement doesn't matter.
However, Mr. Chen cannot retire.
What are you saying?
No one in the Imperial Inspectorate
is as important as Mr. Chen.
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪